A big misconception is that if your dog's tale is waging, is that he's happy.
Alot of dogs wag their tales when they are ready to attack as well, so the big thing to notice is where your dog's tail is.
Like if his tail is tucked, then he's afraid and you should not be petting him at that time and you should not be petting him at that time.
You never pet a dog when he is afraid, because that will make him more afraid.
If it is laying loosey like this, this is just normal.
When he's waging his tail and it's out here in the middle, that means he's happy, that's a normal state of mind.
When the tail starts to go up and it starts to wag like this, your dog is probably in a more aggressive state of mind.
Another thing about dogs, when you're walking them, you'll see their ears perk up, if their ears perk up, that's them paying more attention.
But you can see a lot of times that they will get this intense stare when they are fixating on something and when they are fixating on something, that's when you need to correct them because that's them being obsessed with that object whether it be a person, or another dog, or anything like that.
So, it's ok for dogs to look and be curious, but if they get that intense obssessive stare, then it's going to be threatened.